Let's move towards a big and exclusive
news. Our correspondent Anurag Shah is
joining us in the program. He is
telling us
a big and obscene news related to the insurance sector. Anurag, tell me, do
you have any
big news related to the general insurance industry? Just like the general
insurance companies once make a statement, the
major part is the motor third
party region and there has been no change
in the motor part third party premium since 2019
and
according to this rule, the rates change every year
but it is
proposed that a big increase in the rates within 2030
but because of that they did not get scared because of who knows why
it did not increase. Then
comes the third one where the companies have now
sent a proposal to the insurance regulator IRDA and in this proposal, an
increase of 15 to 20 percent has been proposed. The
rationale behind this is clear that there are
many companies whose solvency has fallen
below the prescribed standard because there are a
lot of reclaims coming in the major part of the motor sector and for the third consecutive
year they have been increasing their premium rates.  They were
unable to increase the rates, but other than that, the
companies also say that the prices
seem to be increasing, and
underwriting is currently underway. If we
talk about two-wheelers, the vehicles
being sold are being given coverage until 2036,
but the rates are
for 2019, so this is proving to be a burden on the companies.
Anjali Inch and
Id have been given by the companies, and
it is also believed that if there is no increase for the third consecutive year, then the
pressure on the companies will increase significantly. The
statement of these two motor third parties is a very
big judgment. The overall premium in the
life insurance sector in companies is up
to 25 percent of that, which is for
motor third parties.
Considering this, this time the companies are
hopeful that the
changes in rates that happen every third year, the
mandatory rates change every year, will be done
because now the motor
third party policies sold for new
vehicles have long-term
underwriting.  In the houses of 2019,
right now the vehicles are being sold in January 2005,
quality is being given there, the
election conduct of 2025 is for four wheelers and till 2036
for two wheelers, so looking at all these nationals, the
companies believe that this time
they will get relief and
two author approvals will be given
by ID to increase the premium rates, so this eclipse which will be a good news for the drivers and
their news but for the companies, to some
extent this is a big news for you,
preparation to pay insurance premium, there is no increase
in third party insurance after 2019,
now there is preparation to increase, this is a good
news for India Insurance and
also for partner ICICI Lombard.